Another descriptive attributes of common risk factors,
常见风险因子的另一个特性是
is that they are well known by the investment community.
投资者对它们都很熟悉
This is not just a descriptive attribute,
这不仅仅是一种特性
it also affects how risk factors drive price movements.
而且会改变风险因子对股价变化的影响
When most of the investors in the market understand
当市场上的大部分投资者
how a factor drives the price movement of a stock,
知道因子如何推动股价变化时
then it's unlikely that anyone will gain
那么任何人都不太可能
a competitive advantage in generating higher than expected returns based on that factor.
根据该因子获得有力的竞争优势并产生高于预期的收益
Why is that? Because investors who are seeking to maintain
为何会这样？因为希望取得竞争优势的投资者
a competitive position will monitor the movements of these risk factors,
将会监控这些风险因子的变化
and we'll adjust their portfolios in response to changes in these factors.
并且根据这些因子的变化调整投资组合
Researchers have looked into how the performance of funds that use
研究人员研究了为何当学术论文广泛宣传特定因子后
particular factors declines after those factors are widely published in academic papers.
使用该因子的基金业绩就会下降
For example, the findings that small-cap stocks tend to have
例如小盘股往往收益率比大盘股高
higher returns than large-cap stocks is also known as the size effect.
这个规律也称为规模效应
Research that details this effect was first published in 1981.
详细描述这种效应的研究论文首次发表于 1981 年
A mutual fund was actually created to make use of the size factor
有个共同基金就是专门利用这种规模因子
and it was called the dimensional fund advisor small company portfolio.
称为 dimensional fund advisor small company portfolio
In a study conducted in 2003,
2003 年的一项研究表明
researchers showed how this particular funds performance after the 1981 publication,
在 1981 年论文发表之后
no longer generated abnormal returns based on the size factor.
这个基金不再因为规模因子而产生超额收益
One likely explanation, is that the act of publishing
一种可能的解释是
the size factor and its ability to generate abnormal returns,
规模因子论文指出这种因子能够产生超额收益率后
made the size factor well-known to practitioners at investment funds.
投资基金的从业者都知道了这种规模因子
The practitioners then acted on this knowledge and over time,
然后从业者开始采取行动
traded away this mispricing.
慢慢地 交易行为导致这种效应逐渐消失
That is one consequence of being risk factors.
这就是风险因子的一种后果
They're not likely to be used to enhance the portfolio return.
它们不太可能用于增强投资组合收益率
In other words, risk factors may give an indication for how much
换句话说 风险因子可以告诉我们
the portfolio stocks bounce up and down like boats without sails,
投资组合股票上涨和下跌多少
moving up and down with the ocean waves.
如同没有帆的船只随着大海波浪上下颠簸
However, just as a boat without sales
但是 就像没有帆的船只
can't drive its average position in a particular direction,
无法使平均位置朝着特定方向变化一样
an investor won't use risk factors to drive their returns in a particular direction.
投资者不会使用风险因子推动收益率朝着特定方向变化
To summarize the idea,
总结下
we say that risk factors are drivers of portfolio variance,
风险因子是投资组合方差的推动因素
but not drivers of the portfolio's mean return.
但不是投资组合均值收益的推动因素